{"tossups": [{"question": "A thinker from this country founded structural anthropology with works like<em> The Elementary</em> <em>Structures of Kinship</em>. Another thinker from this country founded a \u201creligion of humanity\u201d and formulated a \u201claw of three stages,\u201d espousing philosophical positivism.<em> The Elementary Structures of Religious Life</em> was written by a sociologist from this country who pioneered the field with a work examining suicide. For ten points, name this home country of the thinkers Auguste Comte, Claude Levi-Strauss, and \u00b4Emile [ay-MEEL] Durkheim.", "answer": "<b> France</b>", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Sociology"}, {}, {"question": "This event led to the formation of the Dewey Commission, which exonerated one of its victims. Other victims of this event were accused of assassinating Sergey Kirov and included the right-wing Nikolai Bukharin. A photo was changed after this event to exclude Nikolai Yezhov, who was responsible for the worst actions of this event. The NKVD carried out most of the executions during this event, which aimed to get rid of the supporters of Leon Trotsky. For ten points, name this cleansing of the Soviet government just prior to World War II.", "answer": "<b> Great Purge</b> (prompt on descriptions related to \u201cMoscow show trials\u201d until Yezhov is mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A scholar who lived in this city wrote<em> The True Intellectual System of the Universe</em> and was a rival of Thomas Hobbes; that man was Ralph Cudworth. This city names a group of Platonist 17th-Century philosophers and a group that included Anthony Blunt and Kim Philby, a spy ring known as this city\u2019s namesake \u201cfive.\u201d Isaac Newton attended Trinity College in, for ten points, what British city whose historic university is a rival of Oxford?", "answer": "<b> Cambridge</b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "Amphibious landings near this city were a key part of Exercise Zapad-81, the USSR\u2019s largest military exercise. In January 2019, this city\u2019s progressive mayor, Pawel Adamowicz [pav-el adam-oh-vitz], was stabbed and killed. Shipyard workers in this city chanted \u201cBring Anna Walentynowicz [vah-went-ee-no-vitz] Back to Work!\u201d in 1980 during a strike at the Lenin Shipyard. The Solidarity movement began in, for ten points, what Polish port city?", "answer": "<b> Gdansk</b> (accept<b> Danzig</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "In this decade, the Lafollette Commission revealed that the Pinkertons had spies in \u201cpractically every union in the country.\u201d John Lewis negotiated the recognition of the UAW by General Motors after the Flint sit-down strike in this decade. Yellow Dog contracts were outlawed in this decade, in which the Wagner Act codified the right to unionize. The CCC planted trees to ameliorate the Dust Bowl in, for ten points, what decade in which Franklin Roosevelt introduced the New Deal?", "answer": "<b> 1930</b>s (prompt on \u201cthirties\u201d)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Peter Greyson partially destroyed a copy of one of these documents by pouring red paint mixed with glue on it. The 7/50 formula concerns changes to one of these documents in Canada. The Indian version of this document is the longest in the world, and the American version includes a Revenue Clause, noting that spending bills begin in the House of Representatives. The Articles of Confederation were replaced with, for ten points, what type of governing law?", "answer": "<b> constitution</b> (accept additional information, like Canada\u2019s<b> Constitution</b>)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "These people were the target of a seawall built by Pompeo Targone, which withstood an assault from Henri de Rohan. A leader of these people, Gaspard de Coligny, was killed on the orders of Catherine de Medici during the St. Bartholomew\u2019s Day Massacre. These followers of John Calvin were stripped of their religious tolerance by the Edict of Fontainebleau, many years after it was first granted by Henry IV\u2019s Edict of Nantes. For ten points, name this group of French Protestants.", "answer": "<b> Huguenot</b>s (prompt on descriptions of French Protestants/Calvinists and partial answers thereof)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Negotiations for this treaty occurred concurrently with those of the Treaty of Hubertusburg. Charles III\u2019s refusal to cede Cuba led to Spain relinquishing Florida as part of this agreement, which was largely negotiated by the Duc de Choiseul. In this treaty, Guadalupe and Martinique were kept by a party that ceded all of its mainland holdings west of the Mississippi River. Much of New France was ceded to England in, for ten points, what treaty ending the Seven Years\u2019 War?", "answer": "1763 Treaty of<b> Paris</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "The first ruler of this dynasty legendarily ordered his soldiers to raise copies of the Quran on their lances, in declaring a truce at the Battle of Siffin; that ruler later came to power after the Kharijites caused the downfall of his main rival. This dynasty fell from power after a defeat at the Battle of the Zab and the subsequent death of Marwan II. This caliphate was founded by Muawiyah after the assassination of the last Rashidun caliph, Ali. For ten points, name this Islamic caliphate that was ruled from Damascus and which preceded the Abbasids.", "answer": "<b> Umayyad</b> Caliphate", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man recited the song \u201cWhat Do You Do With the Mad that You Feel?\u201d in a Congressional hearing chaired by John Pastore, who declared this man\u2019s testimony \u201cwonderful\u201d and said \u201cLooks like you just earned the $20 million.\u201d Tom Hanks will portray this man in a 2019 film, a year after an acclaimed Morgan Neville documentary about this man became the highest-grossing biographic documentary of all time. For ten points, name this sweater-wearing late children\u2019s television host, the subject of the films,<em> A</em> <em>Beautiful Day in the Neighborhood</em> and<em> Won\u2019t You Be My Neighbor?</em>.", "answer": "Fred<b> Rogers</b> (or Mister<b> Rogers</b>)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {"question": "The Canadian hundred dollar bill depicts a woman observing this compound through a microscope. A scientist remarked that it had gotten \u201cthe disulphides right\u201d upon seeing Dorothy Hodgkin\u2019s X-ray crystallographic structure of this compound, which helped him confirm the chemical structure of this compound\u2019s A and B chains. After blocking off pancreatic ducts in dogs, Charles Best and Frederick Banting used extracts containing this compound to reduce blood sugar. For ten points, name this protein hormone that is used to treat diabetes.", "answer": "<b> insulin</b>", "metadata": "Science - Biology"}, {}, {"question": "C\u00b4ecile Renault was executed for being caught meeting this man while carrying knives. After the fall of this man, the Muscadins led the First White Terror to eliminate his supporters. This man created a holiday, held on the anniversary of the Champ de Mars Massacre, for his Cult of the Supreme Being. This man\u2019s death led to the Thermidorean Reaction, and he was a member of the Committee of Public Safety alongside ally Louis St. Just. For ten points, name this Jacobin leader who led the Reign of Terror until he, too, was guillotined.", "answer": "Maximillian<b> Robespierre</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "During the Revolutionary War, Edward Hand helped delay the British invasion of this state\u2019s Throg\u2019s Neck peninsula. At a battle in this state, the forces of John Sullivan faced bombardments while stationed at Battle Pass. The quote \u201cI only regret that I have but one life to lose for my country\u201d was legendarily given by Nathan Hale before he was hanged in this state. William Howe forced George Washington to retreat at a 1776 battle in this state that took place in King\u2019s County. For ten points, name this state, the site of the Battle of Long Island.", "answer": "<b> New York</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This artist, who appealed to Republican sentiments with his painting</b><em><b> Lictors Bring to </b><b>Brutus the Bodies of His Sons</b></em><b>, produced a propaganda piece in which stones are inscribed with the words (+) \u201cCarolus Magnus\u201d and \u201cHannibal.\u201d This man depicted a revolutionary clutching a pen in his bathtub after he was stabbed by Charlotte Corday, then depicted his later patron (*) </b> crossing the Alps at the Saint Bernard Pass. For ten points, name this French artist who painted<em> The Coronation of Napoleon and Josephine</em> and<em> The Death of Marat</em>.", "answer": "Jacques-Louis<b> David</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b>This man was replaced in his early career by Don Carlos Buell after a visit with Secretary of War Simon Cameron convinced the general public that this man was insane. This man\u2019s</b> <b>Special Field Orders Number (+)</b> <b>15 was interpreted as a promise of \u201cforty acres and a</b> <b>mule,\u201d and he notably destroyed railway tracks by wrapping them around trees to make a namesake (*)</b> \u201cnecktie.\u201d This man helped turn the 1864 election for Lincoln when he captured the\u201cChristmas present\u201d of Savannah. For ten points, name this Union general who led the \u201cMarch to the Sea.\u201d", "answer": "William Tecumseh<b> Sherman</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This battle\u2019s winning side took the Boedromia festival, which celebrated Theseus beating the Amazons, and changed it to celebrate this victory. A delay in this battle was prompted</b> <b>when it was found that reinforcements could not come until the (+)</b> <b>Karneia [kar-nye-uh]</b> <b>festival ended. The winning side in this battle struck after Callimachus broke a tied vote in favor of attacking, thus turning back an invasion sent by (*)</b> Darius the Great. Athens prevailed over the Persian Empire in, for ten points, what 490 BC battle whose result was reported by Pheidippides after running 26 miles?", "answer": "Battle of<b> Marathon</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "<b>The Canadian Norman Bethune was embedded as a doctor in this man\u2019s army. This man</b> <b>was profiled in the most famous work of Edgar Snow. Five Encirclement (+)</b> <b>Campaigns</b> <b>attempted and failed to defeat this leader, who compromised with an opponent after that opponent was kidnapped in the (*) </b> Xi\u2019an [shee-ahn] Incident. This leader moved to a new base in Jiangxi during the Long March. For ten points, name this longtime Chinese communist leader.", "answer": "<b> Mao</b> Zedong", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>Housesteads is a particularly well-preserved fort along this structure, whose milecastles were typically flanked by two turrets. A series of tablets were found near this structure\u2019s</b> <b>fort of Vindolanda. The River (+)</b> <b>Tyne was the starting point of this structure, which</b> <b>terminated at Solway Firth. This structure, whose construction started in 122 AD, was intended to (*) </b> keep out the Picts and Britons from the Roman Empire. For ten points, name this defensive structure, built by a namesake Roman Emperor who succeeded Trajan.", "answer": "<b> Hadrian\u2019s Wall</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "<b>While vice president, a man from this state reported to Fort McClary to take over as his Coast Guard Company\u2019s cook. John Nutting and John Calef led a British strategy to create \u201cNew Ireland\u201d in this state. The (+) Mulligan Letters helped tarnish a presidential campaign for a politician from this state. The Webster-Ashburton Treaty settled a war in this state over border disputes, the (*) </b> Aroostook War. The home state of Hannibal Hamlin and\u201cContinental Liar\u201d James Blaine is, for ten points, what state that was admitted to the Union in the Missouri Compromise, breaking off of Massachusetts?", "answer": "<b> Maine</b> <b>Extra Question</b> Only read if you need a backup or tiebreaker!", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}